# **Armando José Arenas Sánchez**

## Fullstack Developer

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/armando-arenas 🌎 https://github.com/ArmandoTech

#### **About me**

I'm a college dropout of my bachelor of Chemical Engineering. I approved 3 years (6 semesters) with special distinctions for my GPA and proposals of being a tutor for engineering subjects due to my skills.

I decided to quit college when I realized that I loved coding. After this, I dedicated myself to study fulltime web and software development.

## Languages

**Spanish English** 

Native C2 Proficient (EF SET)

#### **Skills**

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript ES6+, Node-Express, React, API REST, Python, Django, Insomnia, MongoDB, Mongoose, SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Docker, Sequelize, Sonarqube, Experience with agile methodoligies, Mantis Bug Tracker, Git and Github.

#### **Professional Experience**

## FRONTEND ENGINEER | QUALITY ASSURANCE,

11/2022 - 01/2023 | Remote

Enciso Systems ☑

Implemented features on NoirLab's FitsLiberator desktop app. Refactor code from the European Southern Observatory (ESO) and the Internacional Astronomic Union's (IAU) websites looking for vulnerabilities, bugs, etc. (Sonarqube, React, Electron, Docker, Django).

#### **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER,** *Biofile S.A.S* □

10/2022 - Present | Remote

Implemented new functionalities on clients' software and maintenance of databases (SQL Server, JQuery, Crystal Reports, .NET). Mentorship role with new members of the development team.

FREELANCER 2

04/2022 – 06/2022 | Bucaramanga, Colombia

Informative website for a mechanical workshop (HTML5, CSS3, Javascript).

#### **Education**

**Self-Taught,** *Platzi* | *Udemy* 

2020 - Present | Online

30+ Certificates of Completion on web and software development.

**Chemical Engineering,** *Industrial University of Santander* 

2019 – 2022 | Bucaramanga, Colombia

Dropout from the program when was about to start the fourth year. Special distinction for 4.54/5.0 GPA.

## **Projects**

## Restaurant's API 🛮

Part of the back-end team who developed an API which was used on the production for a restaurant app.

## Chat-App 🛮

Real-time chat using Javascript and relational databases.

## Online Store's API

API with the functionality to be used for store's purposes.

## **Servicoches ☑**

Informative web page for a mechanical workshop. Allows appoinment booking with email.js.

#### **AmericanGrill**

Demo of a restaurant's website located on Bucaramanga, Colombia.